so now we will go through several types
of
multiprocessors the first type of
multiprocessor uses what is called a
centralized shared memory so all the
cores let's say we have four of them
might have their own caches but then
they're all connected to the same bus so
they can all access the same main memory
and input output devices this scores can
share data by simply reading and writing
the main memory assuming of course that
these reads and wrs go through the
caches properly and we will see that we
can achieve that so pretty much this
score can send data to this score by
writing to some memory location and then
this score reads it from there similarly
any of the cores can access any of the
io devices here this type of a system is
really what today's multicore processors
tend to look like and is also called
Yuma which stand stands for uniform
memory access time but it's not umat
it's just Yuma but what is uniform is
really the time to access the memory why
well because this main
memory is at the same long distance from
all of the cores yes it can be slightly
closer to some of them but because
they're all connected to it in the same
way the memory really is about as bad to
access as any one of them this type of
multiprocessing is also called SM SMP
which stands for symmetric
multiprocessor it's called symmetric
because any core and its cache look just
like any other core and its cache in the
system so if we had two cores we can
just take one of them with its caches
and replicate to make a four core system